Guide to the Peter H. Sera papers, 1964-1986 MS2183
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Peter H. Sera papers
1964-1986
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Sera, Peter H.
MS2183
16.5 Linear Feet
This collection was donated by Peter H. Sera in 1990 and contains material pertaining to telecommunications and satellite broadcasting from 1964-1989.
Biographical Note
Peter H. Sera, born in 1937, was a lieutenant colonel in the United State Marine Corps from 1960-1987. He was transferred from active duty to reserve status in 1964, at which point he pursued work in the fields of computers, telecommunications, and industrial management with IBM, AT&T, NL Industries, Ryder Systems, and Satellite Broadcasting Systems (SBS), amongst others. He worked in many areas throughout his career including sales, consulting, systems analysis and planning assignments. Most significantly he served as a program manager at SBS from 1980-1986 and was involved with carrier relations, configuration-database management, business planning, and systems implementation of satellite based networks and services.
The highlights of his career include placing communication satellites, as well as Space Station Freedom (now known as the International Space Station) into orbit.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains records for Satellite Business Systems (SBS) including business interactions with other companies such as IBM, Texas Instruments, and Southwestern Bell, among others. The collection contains correspondence, conference materials, reports, and technical publications, as well as material about other devices and technological systems dating from 1964-1986. There are also files related to Mr. Sera's time with other companies including Ryder Systems and NL Industries, including documents pertaining to telecommunications and corporate Centrex.
Arrangement
Organized into 4 series: Satellite Business Systems; NL Industries, Telecommunications Division; Other Companies; and Technology: Devices and Systems
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Peter H. Sera, 1990 [1990.002]. Given with the purpose of providing research material for the Telecommunications graduate program at GW.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Artificial satellites in telecommunication; Telecommunication; Sera, Peter H.
- Satellite Business Systems (SBS), 1980-1986
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials from Peter Sera's employment at Satellite Business Systems (SBS) from 1980-1986. It contains correspondence, reports, and technical publications related to topics such as network installation and carrier relations, amongst others.
  - Satellite Business System (SBS) - Acronyms and Abbreviations, 1979-1985; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Automation, 1980-1982; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Budgets, 1985 May 29, July 8; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carrier Relations, 1983-1986; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Computer Services-Users Guide and Utilities Guide, 1983-1985; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Development of Corporate NPA/NXX Database, 1984-1986; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - CR FG D EOS (Carrier Relations Feature Group D EOS)-Serving Area Report, 1984-1985; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CR FG D (Carrier Relations Feature Group D) General, 1984-1986; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CR FG D (Carrier Relations Feature Group D) Products-Skyline Long Distance Service, 1984-1985; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - CR FG D (Carrier Relations Feature Group D) Tandem, 1984 October-December; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - CR (Carrier Relations)-General, 1985 May-June; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - CR (Carrier Relations)-Regions, 1985-1986; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - CR (Carrier Relations)-Status/Reports, 1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Customer Quality Assurance, 1981 May 5; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Drafts, Undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Expense Reports, 1981-1985; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Field Service, 1983-1985; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Forms, 1980-1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General Information about Launchin Satellites into Space, 1980-1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Index of Files, 1980; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Job Descriptions, 1981-1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Logistics, 1980 July; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Human Resources and Communications, 1982; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - NN (National Network) Customer Technical Services, 1980-1982; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - National Network Engineering, 1984 February 7; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Network Engineering, 1980-1984; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - National Network Design, 1985-1986; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - National Network Services and Central Office Engineering, 1980-1981, 1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - New Employee Information and Benefits, 1980-1981, 1984-1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - National Network Services, 1986 February 14; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - National Network (NN) Customer Service Operations, 1981-1982; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - National Network (NN) Service Management and Development, 1984-1986; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - National Network (NN) Marketing, 1982-1984; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - National Network (NN) Business Office, 1982-1985; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - National Network (NN) Customer Technical Services, 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - NNSD Marketing Operations Equal Access, 1984-1985; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - NNSD Equal Access Bell Operating Company (BOC) Activities, 1984-1985; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - NNSD Equal Access Business Office Support, 1985 June 3; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - NNSD Equal Access Marketing Support, 1985; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - NNSD Equal Access Project Administration, 1984-1986; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Orbiter" Newsletter, 1982-1986; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Organizational Information, 1980, 1986; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Plans, 1982-1982, 1986; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Project/Task Log, 1980 March; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Tariff (Prototype), 1980 February 29; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Telephone Directories, 1980 October; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Trip Reports and Itineraries, 1981; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Training, 1980-1985; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- NL Industries, Telecommunications Division, 1968-1979
  This series contains telecommunications materials related to Peter Sera's employment at NL Industries, as well as documents pertaining to corporate Centrex. It ranges from 1968-1979.
  - Baroid Division-Administrator, 1973-1976; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Administration and Management, 1971, 1974-1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Budget and Expenses, 1974-1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Corporate-Centrex, 1974-1976; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Corporate-Centrex-Correspondence, 1975; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Corporate-Centrex-Dialing Instructions, 1974-1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Corporate-Centrex-Directory, 1977-1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Corporate-Centrex-Meetings, 1975 June 16, 20; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Corporate-Centrex-Publicity, 1971-1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Corporate-Centrex-Station Design, 1975 July 15; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Corporate-Centrex-Station Features, 1972, 1975; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Corporate-Centrex-Supply Service and Equipment, 1975; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Check List, 1969-1979; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Computer Reports, 1974-1979; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Communications Contacts, 1974-1975; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1978; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cost Reduction and Control, 1971-1975; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5 (1/2))
  - Cost Reductions and Control, 1960-1975; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6 (2/2))
  - Data Planning, Analysis, Design, 1974-1978; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 7 (1/2))
  - Data Planning, Analysis, Design, 1968-1978; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 8 (2/2))
  - Data Trouble Shooting and Fault Isolation, 1971, 1975-1978; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Directives, 1975 June 24; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Educational Aids and Other Supplies, 1975-1977; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Expense Reports, 1975-1979; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Blank Forms, 1970-1978; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5 (1/3))
  - Blank Forms, 1972-1977; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 6 (2/3))
  - Blank Forms, 1977-1979; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 7 (3/3))
  - International, 1971-1979; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Itinerary, 1979; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Job Descriptions, 1972-1973, 1979; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Maps and Schedules, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Meetings, 1971-1976; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Management Information System (MIS) Charter, 1969-1974; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous and General Information, 1970-1978; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Monthly Activity Reports, 1977-1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Objectives, 1970-1977; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Plans, 1969, 1974-1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Policies, Guidelines, and Standards, 1960, 1969-1975; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Position Descriptions, 1969-1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Telemanagement Program, 1974-1976; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1 (1/3))
  - Telemanagement Progrm, 1972-1973; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2 (2/3))
  - Telemanagement Program, 1969-1972; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3 (3/3))
  - Publications, 1970, 1977-1979; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Questionnaires, Surveys and Studies, 1959-1978; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 5(1/2))
  - Questionnairse, Surveys, and Studies, 1969-1978; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 6 (2/2))
  - Rates, 1971-1978; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Recruiting and Hiring, 1969-1979; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 8 (1/2))
  - Recruiting and Hiring, 1974-1979; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 9(2/2))
  - Rough Drafts, 1975 April 5; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Seminars and Courses, 1970-1977; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Services and Equipment Expenses, 1974-1977; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - TDX User's Guide, 1977-1978; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Teleconferencing, 1978; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Training and Applications, 1965-1978; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Travel Expense Report-Blank, 1978; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Other Companies, 1968-1986
  Arranged alphabetically.This collection contains records for Satellite Business Systems including business interactions with other companies such as IBM, Texas Instruments, and Southwestern Bell, among others. The collection contains correspondence, conference materials, reports, and technical publications related to topics such as network installation, message service description documents, driver 8 refurbishment, as well as material about other devices and technological systems dating from 1964-1989. There are also files related to Mr. Sera's time with other companies including Ryder Systems and NL Industries, including documents pertaining to telecommunications and corporate Centrex.
  This series contains mostly technical publications, as well as user guides, reports and forms pertaining to companies (and their devices) with whom Peter Sera did business at NL Industries and Satellite Business System (SBS) from 1968-1986. It also includes material related to his employment with Ryder System in 1979.
  - Advanced Communications Services (ACS), 1978; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - American Satellite, 1978; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Ameritech, 1985; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - AT&T, 1982-1985; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 11 (1/4))
  - AT&T Long Lines New York City, 1971-1978; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 12 (2/4))
  - AT&T Long Lines New York City, 1969-1978; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 13(3/4))
  - AT&T New York City (195 Broadway), 1968-1978; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 1 (4/4))
  - Bell Atlantic, 1985-1986; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bell South, 1985 May 16; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Brindlee Mountain Telephone Company (BMTC), 1984 June 22; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Competitive Carriers, 1984-1985; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Compuscan, 1978; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Coopers and Lybrand, 1976 April; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Datapoint Corporation, 1978; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Divestiture, 1983-1985; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - DMW Group, 1977-1978; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Electronic Tandem Network (ETN/ETS/FP-8), Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 11 (1/2))
  - Electronic Tandem Network (ETN/ETS/FP-8), 1978-1979; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 12 (2/2))
  - Emory Ayers Associates, 1978 October 13; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - FCC and Other Government Agencies, 1977-1979; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Federal Communications Commission (FCC), 1980-1985; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Franklin Systems, 1978; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - General Electric (GE)-Mobile, 1976; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - General Telephone and Electronics Corporation (GT&E), 1975-1977; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - IDC-International Data Corporation, 1979; Series 3 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - International Business Machines Corporation (IBM), 1971-1977; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Intelligent Network Surveillance and Administration Center (INSAC), 1977-1979; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - International Graphics, 1978; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Intertel, 1977-1978; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - ITT-Communications Equipment, 1977; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - ITT-International Telex, 1975; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Motorola, 1976-1977; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - MCI Communications, 1976-1978; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Network Analysis Corporation (NAC), 1977-1979; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - New Jersey Bell (Newark), 1971-1979; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Northern Telecom Inc. (NTI), 1981; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Northern Telecom, 1974; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - NYNEX, 1984-1986; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Pacific Teleis, 1983-1985; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Panafax, 1978; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Paradyne, 1978; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - RCA-International Telex, 1971-1978; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Ryder System Incorporated-Blank Forms, 1979; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Ryder System Incorporated-Corporate Systems and Strategic Plan, 1978-1979; Series 3 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Ryder System Incorporated-Costs: Computing and Telecom, 1979; Series 3 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Ryder System Incorporated-Instructional Program Series, 1979; Series 3 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Ryder System Incorporated-Progress and Status Reports, 1976-1979; Series 3 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Ryder System Incorporated-Salary and Hourly Administration Performance Appraisal, 1979; Series 3 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Ryder System Incorporated-Telecom Services: Analysis, Acquisition, and Costs, 1974, 1978-1979; Series 3 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Service/Group 800, 1975-1978; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Southern New England Telephone Company (SNET), 1984-1985; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Southwestern Bell, 1985; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Storage Technology Corporation (STC) Communications, 1978; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Telco Research Corporation (TRC), 1979; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Telecom-Miscellaneous, 1973, 1976, 1979; Series 3 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Telenet Communications, 1976, 1979; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Texas Instruments (TI), 1978; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - U.S. West, 1985; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Vydec, 1977-1978; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Western Union International, Inc. (WUI), 1978; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Western Union Telegraph, 1973-1977; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Xerox, 1971-1977; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Technology: Devices and Systems, 1964-1986
  This series contains reference manuals, user guides, conference materials, reports, and technical publications pertaining to a variety of devices and systems within the fields of communication and satellite broadcasting from 1964-1986.
  - Series 11,000 Incorporated, 1969-1972; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "abc of the Telephone Course Workbook", 1985; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Acceptance Tests-Voice Frequency (VF) Facilities and Access L., 1980 September 22; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - ACD Systems- Automatic Call Distribution, 1979; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - "American Management Associations 50th Anniversary" - Notes and Device Information, 1973; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Automated Business Communications - 1979 Invitationals Conference, Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 7 (1/2))
  - Automated Business Communications-1979 Invitational Conference, Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 8 (2/2))
  - Assigning Procedure: Circuit Associated, 1980 May 16; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Batteries, 1980, 1983; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Bell System Instruction/Reference Manual for PBX and Centrex, 1964 September; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 1 (1/4))
  - Bell System Instruction/Reference Manual for PBX and Centrex, 1964 September; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 2(2/4))
  - Bell System Instruction/Reference Manual for PBX and Centrex, 1964 September; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 3(3/4))
  - Bell System Instruction/Reference Manual for PBX and Centrex, 1964 September; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 4 (4/4))
  - BM-Burst Modem, 1980-1981; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - CAM-Configuration Analysis and Management, 1980 May; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - CCSA-Common Control Switching Arrangement, 1971-1979; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - CCSA-Common Control Switching Arrangement Reference Manual, 1967 June; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Center for Communications Management Incorporated Binder-WATS (Wide Area Telecommunications Service), Business Telecommunication, 1974-1975; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - CIM-Customer Installation Management, 1980 September-November; Series 4 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - CIR-Customer Installation Requirements, 1980 September-October; Series 4 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - CNMF-Customer Network Management Facility, 1981 May 5; Seres 4 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - CNS-Communications Network Service A, 1984 July; Series 4 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - CNS-Communications Network Service B Customers, 1981, 1984; Series 4 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - CNS-Communications Network Service B, 1982-1983; Series 4 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - CODEC-New and Old Voice, 1981 July 7; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Commercial Software, 1978-1979; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Communications Managers Association of New York Binder, 1979 January 2; Series 4 (Box 15, Folder 5(1/3))
  - Communications Managers Association of New York Binder, 1979 January 2; Series 4 (Box 15, Folder 6(2/3))
  - Communications Managers Association of New York Binder, 1979 January 2; Series 4 (Box 15, Folder 7(3/3))
  - Communications Planning Binder, 1974 June; Series 4 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Communications Preplanning Binder, 1970-1973; Series 4 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - The Conference Institute Binder with Communications Notes and Information, 1970 August 31; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Communications Word Processing, 1977-1979; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Controlling Telephone Costs-An AMA Management Briefing Binder, 1972 April; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Corporate Policy Manual, 1970-1976; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Corporate Wide Studies, 1977-1979; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - COTS-Circuit Order Tracking System, 1982; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - CPES-Customer Premises Earth Station, 1980-1981; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - CPES Equipment Rack and Floor Space Analysis, 1980 July 8; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Cutover Switch (Trunk Splitter), 1980; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Data Aggregator, 1980-1983; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - DCAS-Data Collection and Administrative System, 1982; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Data Communications Binder-Articles and Publications, 1966-1976; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Data Communications-Publications, 1974-1976; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Data Communications-Ryder System Incorporated, 1979; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Data Communications Service and Equipment, 1977 March; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Data Experiences Seminar-Notes and Presentations, 1981 June 25; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Data Manager-IRM Binder, 1985 September 23; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Data-Phone/Data Speed-Correspondence and Device Information, 1973-1977; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Data Strategy Taks Force Report Binder, 1980 April 30; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 4(1/2))
  - Data Strategy Task Force Report Binder, 1980 April 30; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 5(2/2))
  - Data Test Equipment, 1975-1979; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - DEMARC, 1981 March 23; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Disaster Recovery-SBS, 1981-1982; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 1(1/3))
  - Disaster Recovery-SBS, 1982; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 2(2/3))
  - Disaster Recovery-SBS, 1982; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 3(3/3))
  - DMS-100 Family, Digital Multiplex System Applications Guide, 1981; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - DNS-Data Network Services, 1982 June 23; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Driver 8 Refurbishment/Migration Plan, 1981-1982; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - DTS-Digital Termination Service, 1981 November; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - EC-Echo Cancellers, 1980-1982; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - EMI-Electormagnetic Interference Surveys, 1980 June 16, 20; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Engineering Objectives Document and Shared Services, 1980 July 22; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - ERL-Equipment Requisition List, 1980-1981; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - ESS-Electronic Switching System 101, 1976-1979; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 11(1/2))
  - ESS-Electronic Switching System 101, 1976-1979; Series 4 (Box 18, Folder 12(2/2))
  - Exchange Services Division SBS Reference Manual, 1981; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 1(1/3))
  - Exchange Services Division SBS Reference Manual, 1981; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 2(2/3))
  - Exchange Services Division SBS Reference Manual Binder, 1981; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 3(3/3))
  - Facility Planning Manual, 1980 June 2; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Facsimile, 1971-1979; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Facsimile-Trials and Evaluation Programs 1972-1973, 1971-1977; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - FES-Front End Switch, 1981; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Field Practices, 1981-1982; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Floor Plans-Equipment Layouts, 1980-1981; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Florida Public Service Commission-Telephone Service Standards, 1979; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - FO-Fiber Optic IFL(Inter-Facility Links), 1979-1980, 1984; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - FTN-Multi Transponder Field Test Network, 1982-1983; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - General Motors, 1980-1984; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Grounding Plan, 1982; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - GSA(General Services Administration) Internal Telecommunications Management, 1963, 1969; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Hyrdocaps, 1980; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - IBM Data Communications Concepts and Communications Systems Design Binder, 1964; Series 4 (Box 20, Folder 1(1/2))
  - IBM Data Communications Concepts and Communications Systems Design Binder, 1964; Series 4 (Box 20, Folder 2(2/2))
  - IBM Terminal Handbook Binder, 1964; Series 4 (Box 20, Folder 3(1/2))
  - IBM Terminal Handbook Binder, 1964; Series 4 (Box 20, Folder 4(2/2))
  - IFL-Intrafacilities Link, 1980-1981; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - IML/IPL-Initial Micro/Program Load-Lines and Modem, 1980; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 10)